[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b49c", "question": "Which country was selected as a host of the 1916 Olympic Games, but didn't actually host them?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef96db6ce05a3942286ea2", "question": "Who was the first male actor to be paid a $1 million salary for a movie role?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d60", "question": "Who played the role of TV's T..J. Hooker?", "answer": "William Shatner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8fe9a01dd7bf43be5e85c", "question": "What does \"Veni, vidi, vici\" translate into?", "answer": "I came, I saw, I conquered.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6e1", "question": "What is the more common name for the human tympanic membrane?", "answer": "Eardrum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b0b", "question": "What is the last word of the Bible?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338989", "question": "Who conducted the Philadelphia Orchestra and shook hands with Mickey Mouse in \"Fantasia\"?", "answer": "Leopold Stokowski", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad36", "question": "When first founded by Benjamin Franklin, what was the job of the \"bucket brigade\"?", "answer": "To put out fires", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66261a5bfecdd737e0844", "question": "How far from shore do international waters start?", "answer": "200 nautical miles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b957", "question": "What golfer is nicknamed the \"Golden Bear\"?", "answer": "Jack Nicklaus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef59716ce05a3942286e03", "question": "How long was the sewer pipe that Andy crawled through to freedom in the film \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "500 yards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133950d", "question": "How many planets align during the eclipse in the movie \"Lara Croft: Tomb Raider\"", "answer": "Nine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5fc", "question": "What river begins at Lake Itasca?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51be6ff04d658268c9312", "question": "Who was the husband of the female Judge Deborah in the Bible?", "answer": "Lapidoth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff667ec52a821ff76ae8b00", "question": "The myth that carrots improve your vision is rooted in a propaganda campaign from which war?", "answer": "World War II (To keep the use of radar a secret. British officials launched a campaign stating eating carrots improved night vision.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b604e662d71a53651001", "question": "Which university features a library named in honor of Dr. Seuss?", "answer": "University of California, San Diego", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ae", "question": "In what city would you find Gorky Park?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af99", "question": "What is the name of the slab that became the key for deciphering ancient Egyptian hieroglyphics?", "answer": "The Rosetta Stone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5971ddf989261e916c8e09a0", "question": "Which character from The Simpsons tries to kill Bart Simpson on many occasions?", "answer": "Sideshow Bob", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a4", "question": "Mt. Blanc is the highest peak in what mountain range?", "answer": "The Alps", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e3", "question": "Who is the author of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" novel series?", "answer": "Robert Ludlum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3cf7c73aa70ea0b70af1", "question": "Where will you find the Beagle Channel?", "answer": "In Tierra del Fuego Archipelago on the southern tip of South America between Chile and Argentina.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3d2", "question": "The fruit \"laraha\" is a relative to what better-known fruit?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab8f", "question": "What countries share land borders with Cambodia?", "answer": "Thailand, Laos and Vietnam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba32", "question": "In 1986 what American-born cyclist won his first Tour de France?", "answer": "Greg LeMond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b5", "question": "Who did Ed Wood meet in the movie by the same name?", "answer": "Bela Lugosi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f2b", "question": "Which band member of The Blues Brothers died of drug overdose?", "answer": "John Belushi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3823c73aa70ea0b70acf", "question": "What mode of transportation is Missouri named for?", "answer": "Canoe (An Illinois tribe's phrase for the area's people, \"ouemessourita,\" translates to \u201cwooden canoe people\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a32a", "question": "Which character did Nick Nolte play in the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\"?", "answer": "Jack Cates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9fe", "question": "Tirana is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Albania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5aab2f6058d116dab4aecb49", "question": "Who wrote the line \"East is East, and West is West\"?", "answer": "Rudyard Kipling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ac", "question": "Ants belong to what family?", "answer": "Formicidae", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391cc", "question": "What year was the movie \"Alien\" released?", "answer": "1979", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000f0ff9a72b906b34e3cff", "question": "Cherry, plum and grape are all varieties of which fruit?", "answer": "Tomato", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bb356ef2627b8fe95581be0", "question": "Other than English, what is the main language in Guam?", "answer": "Chamorro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a98", "question": "What early rock and roll pioneer's real first and middle name was Charles Hardin?", "answer": "Buddy Holly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c4", "question": "What element has the chemical symbol Au?", "answer": "Gold", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba53d874c93a3298b214e", "question": "What is the name of Princess Anne's second husband", "answer": "Timothy Laurence", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c53d", "question": "Where in your body is your patella?", "answer": "The knee", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7df", "question": "What are the bumps on the tongue that carry the taste buds called?", "answer": "Papillae", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e17", "question": "What French Wave director plays the UFO expert in \"Close Encounters of the Third Kind\"?", "answer": "Francois Truffaut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b5", "question": "Which studio produced \"Bee Movie\"?", "answer": "DreamWorks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a4", "question": "Natalie Coughlin won six medals in what sport at the 2008 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Swimming", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe77359eec85e375820b305", "question": "Which lake crosses the borders of Vermont, New York, and Canada?", "answer": "Lake Champlain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f6eb9a9e54d890926f6c9", "question": "From what did the Caribbean derive its name?", "answer": "Indigenous people - The word \"Carib\" refers to one of the Amerindian groups on the islands when they were discovered by Europeans.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339459", "question": "Who directed the 2001 movie \"Blow\"?", "answer": "Ted Demme", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a80", "question": "In the Foreigner song \"Hot Blooded\", the singer has a temperature of how many degrees?", "answer": "103", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd9696a23c87fd04dd15e09", "question": "Which historical military commander was never defeated?", "answer": "Alexander the Great", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff14679b0ee8c595b6d39c0", "question": "What classic book inspired the name of Starbucks?", "answer": "Moby Dick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd5e17e83c707845b2167", "question": "What was Charlie Brown's father's profession?", "answer": "Barber", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af72", "question": "The US boycotted the 1980 Olympics to protest what Soviet action?", "answer": "Soviet invasion of Afghanistan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a775", "question": "What famous \"Bay\" is Jamaica's fourth largest city?", "answer": "Montego Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c6", "question": "In what film does Tom Hanks play a character named Sherman McCoy?", "answer": "The Bonfire of the Vanities", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e34", "question": "Who is Rashida Jones' mother?", "answer": "Peggy Lipton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c8", "question": "Which US state has the least rainfall?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df2", "question": "What 1990 dance craze gave the Digital Underground their biggest hit?", "answer": "The Humpty Hump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb91", "question": "How many holes are on a standard Chinese checkers board?", "answer": "121", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af02", "question": "The Continental Army captured Ford Ticonderoga during what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f2", "question": "What note is the highest string of a violin usually tuned to?", "answer": "E", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c450", "question": "What fiber-producing plant is attacked by the boll weevil?", "answer": "Cotton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a695", "question": "What is the official language of Guyana?", "answer": "English", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d63", "question": "Who played the role of TV's B. J. Hunnicut?", "answer": "Mike Farrell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba2f7874c93a3298b2137", "question": "A Villanelle is a type of what?", "answer": "Poem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a63c", "question": "What is the westernmost state in the US?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a17", "question": "Which composer of the \"Rite of Spring\" was still alive to see his music used in Disney's \"Fantasia\"?", "answer": "Igor Stravinsky", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b231", "question": "What kind of animal attacked Jimmy Carter during an April 1979 fishing trip?", "answer": "A rabbit", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2a", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Lagaan\"?", "answer": "Cricket", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b5717bf67df192a942e3358", "question": "Although making its initial appearance in 1938, what year saw the start of mass production of Volkswagen's Beetle?", "answer": "1945", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b4f606d333868d34d6e3", "question": "Which couple is credited with forming the nation of Spain?", "answer": "Ferdinand II of Aragon and Isabella I of Castile", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7bf", "question": "What Pacific Ocean trench is the deepest in the world?", "answer": "Mariana trench", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d2", "question": "What was Murray Langston better known as to the public?", "answer": "The Unknown Comic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c960", "question": "What name is given to a doctor who specializes in skin disorders?", "answer": "Dermatologist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b33a", "question": "On what date did America become an independent nation?", "answer": "July 4th, 1776", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133987a", "question": "In Star Wars, where is Princess Leia from?", "answer": "Alderaan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98e", "question": "In what year did England win its first FIFA World Cup?", "answer": "1966", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a26b", "question": "Who sang the song \"We Didn't Start the Fire\"?", "answer": "Billy Joel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c9", "question": "What French playwright wrote the play \"The Lark\"?", "answer": "Jean Anouilh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7b5", "question": "What do the letters X.O. stand for on a bottle of cognac?", "answer": "Extra Old", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8a93801dd7bf43be5e74a", "question": "Which animal symbolizes good luck in Europe?", "answer": "Ladybug", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b209", "question": "Which 1912 maritime disaster was responsible for numerous changes and improvements in maritime safety?", "answer": "RMS Titanic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ad", "question": "Which rock star plays the role of vampire in the 1983 movie \"The Hunger\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e93a8c6d6f11f394a3b2d58", "question": "In the manga series \"Bleach\", what is the name of Izura Kira's zanpakuto?", "answer": "Wabisuke", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe1", "question": "What is the literal translation of the Greek word \"Utopia\"?", "answer": "No-place", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe73377eec85e375820b221", "question": "What was the name of the antisemitic laws passed in Nazi Germany on September 15, 1935?", "answer": "Nuremberg Law", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5f9", "question": "What US city is nicknamed \"Beantown\"?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e72ccfcd0874f1a5e2d1c26", "question": "What is a \"Winkle Picker\" or \"Winklepicker\"?", "answer": "An English long pointed shoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3c2c54f032c0db195b485", "question": "In 1912, what did a Paris orphanage give away as prizes when it held a raffle to raise money?", "answer": "Live babies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d81", "question": "What two slang terms for oil are used in the \"Beverly Hillbillies\" theme song?", "answer": "Black gold and Texas tea", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be04", "question": "What position was first held by Steve Allen?", "answer": "Tonight Show host", "category": "general"}, {"id": "593c4c1bb8198b9a2b077968", "question": "Who played the title role in the 2013 film \"The Great Gatsby\"?", "answer": "Leonardo DiCaprio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a315", "question": "Who played the role of Samantha Jones on the TV show \"Sex and the City\"?", "answer": "Kim Cattrall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c441", "question": "What is the molten rock magma called once it flows from a volcano?", "answer": "Lava", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdc0d29469bb8041d07a059", "question": "Earl Grey tea is blended with oil extracted from what fruit?", "answer": "Bergamot Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8d6", "question": "Which chemical element has the atomic number 4?", "answer": "Beryllium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ea", "question": "What is it that turns red litmus paper blue?", "answer": "Basic solution", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee7", "question": "How many bottles unexpectedly appear in the last verse of Police song \"Message in a Bottle\"?", "answer": "A hundred billion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2af", "question": "According to the title of the film, what is the profession of Ace Ventura?", "answer": "Pet Detective", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ff", "question": "The Stasi were an intelligence organisation in what country?", "answer": "German Democratic Republic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c888fbde8045e48466db", "question": "What pigment makes plants green?", "answer": "Chlorophyll", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d3", "question": "What New York Yankee was nickname the \"Iron Horse\"?", "answer": "Lou Gehrig", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab0", "question": "During the 1960's, what musician formed and fronted the band \"The Mothers of Invention\"?", "answer": "Frank Zappa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc43", "question": "What famous tennis player became Novak Djokovic's coach in 2013?", "answer": "Boris Becker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ec2a08d98002fdd633b8", "question": "Which singer's autobiography is titled \"Take It Like a Man\"?", "answer": "Boy George's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe3e80338e4e5d4832e6309", "question": "Approximately, how much money did U.S. children spend on war bonds as part of the World War II effort?", "answer": "$1 billion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fea", "question": "In Greek mythology Penthesilea was the queen of which people?", "answer": "Amazons", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc37f6de0eb824d4052ed", "question": "What U.S. state is the smallest by land area?", "answer": "Rhode Island -- At 1214 sq.mi., it is half the size of Miami-Dade County, FL (2431 sq. mi), but has nearly 400 miles of shoreline.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b25fe662d71a53650fd7", "question": "Botticelli's \"Birth of Venus\" features a goddess floating in the ocean on what?", "answer": "Seashell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fedddfd6ce05a3942286da9", "question": "Which popular candy was featured prominently in the classic film \"E.T., the Extra-Terrestrial\"?", "answer": "Hershey Company's Reece's Pieces", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c66f", "question": "What type of bridge is the Golden Gate Bridge?", "answer": "Suspension bridge", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b478", "question": "The Battle of the Plains of Abraham was fought outside which city?", "answer": "Quebec City", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc3", "question": "What did George Harrison's dentist do in April 1965 that changed the face of rock?", "answer": "Gave the Beatles LSD", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e802d7de59ea584496fe99", "question": "In the TV show \"Sabrina the Teenage Witch\", what was the name of Sabrina's cat?", "answer": "Salem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f2", "question": "What modern day country is the Lighthouse of Alexandria located in?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f66", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the Sugarcubes?", "answer": "Bjork", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d0342596a59cbdfbd378", "question": "Who said, \"Nature has given us two ears, two eyes, and but one tongue-to the end that we should hear and see more than we speak\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f2b801dd7bf43be5e812", "question": "What celebrity chef authored mystery novels before they got famous?", "answer": "Anthony Bourdain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391cd", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Alien\"?", "answer": "Ridley Scott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b52a", "question": "What is a vatted malt?", "answer": "A blend of different single malt  whiskies.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c83b", "question": "What Chicago museum features the world's largest Tyrannosaurus Rex skeleton?", "answer": "The Field Museum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae8d", "question": "What Mexican general led the attack against the Alamo?", "answer": "General Antonio Lopez de Santa Anna", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339488", "question": "In what movie does Vianne open a chocolate shop in a small French village?", "answer": "Chocolat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ac", "question": "What New York City landmark is nicknamed \"The Crossroads of the World\"?", "answer": "Times Square", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf9", "question": "What is Henry Kissinger's actual first name?", "answer": "Heinz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe3e67938e4e5d4832e6307", "question": "What term did the British press use to describe the air raids carried out by the Germans in 1940 and 1941?", "answer": "The Blitz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fef", "question": "What is divided into 114 suras?", "answer": "The Quran", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c091", "question": "What are scaup?", "answer": "Ducks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa4", "question": "Who was Oscar-nominated for playing a telegraph boy in \"The Human Comedy\"?", "answer": "Mickey Rooney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c848", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the Sertoli cells?", "answer": "The testes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a7c", "question": "What 1989 hit single contained the following line \"Folks linin' up outside just to get down\"?", "answer": "Love Shack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6e", "question": "What pair of Disney rodents made their debut in the 1943 cartoon \"Private Pluto\"?", "answer": "Chip 'n' Dale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f0", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince\", who does Harry catch tentacula leaves?", "answer": "Professor Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baaf", "question": "What does the TV network abbreviation CBS stand for?", "answer": "Columbia Broadcasting System", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59db76d20ab2c8f322317fe7", "question": "In which ocean or sea are the Seychelles?", "answer": "Indian Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc2f265cee580c7f8fd1e52", "question": "Who said, \"Winners never quit, and quitters never win.\"?", "answer": "Vince Lombardi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a202", "question": "Diane Belmont was the stage name of which famous actress?", "answer": "Lucille Ball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a984", "question": "In what Caribbean country did steel drums originate?", "answer": "Trinidad and Tobago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990f8a6fa5fdd6dd25324ef", "question": "Which city is home to Colman's mustard?", "answer": "Norwich", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eadc3f83302ff91e46480", "question": "How is Alistair Leslie Graham better known as on TV?", "answer": "Ali G", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b44d01dd7bf43be5e7be", "question": "Where is the U.S. vice president's official residence?", "answer": "United States Naval Observatory", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba45", "question": "What is the official state dessert of Massachusetts?", "answer": "Boston Cream Pie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c7", "question": "Which gas has the characteristic smell of rotten eggs?", "answer": "Hydrogen sulfide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af88", "question": "What militant organization was founded in 1966 by Huey Newton and Bobby Seale?", "answer": "Black Panthers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc8", "question": "What brand is known as PFK in French-speaking Quebec?", "answer": "KFC", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3d8", "question": "What moisturizer is derived from sheep's wool?", "answer": "Lanolin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd81c14d0de9af39e9d467f", "question": "Which king was Marie Antoinette married to?", "answer": "Louis XVI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c1", "question": "Who was Spenser's sidekick in the TV show \"Spenser: For Hire\"?", "answer": "Hawk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a955961d1b4d384d5d678", "question": "Which fruit is affected by a grey type of fungus known commonly as Noble Rot?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5fa", "question": "The sleeve insignia of a First Class Petty Officer in the US Navy is a spread eagle over how many chevrons?", "answer": "Three", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e1", "question": "Who directed and acted in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc1573469bb8041d07a08b", "question": "What London landmark did Queen Elizabeth II open up to tourism in 1993?", "answer": "Buckingham Palace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1dd", "question": "What film won the 1944 Oscar for Best Picture?", "answer": "Casablanca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab953a86faa38a764be513", "question": "What year did BMW debut the M5?", "answer": "1985", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a220", "question": "Which tough guy actor was once a linotype operator?", "answer": "Robert Mitchum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b699098e762b54eb9be9412", "question": "How is the number 20 written with Roman numerals?", "answer": "XX", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb74", "question": "An amendment to the US Constitution must be ratified by what fraction of all the states?", "answer": "75%", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b88c", "question": "In which sport is Ukrainian Sergey Bubka best known?", "answer": "Pole vault", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390d9", "question": "What year did Vladimir Nabokov first publish the novel \"Lolita\"?", "answer": "1955", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d4", "question": "The character Randall Flagg is from which novel?", "answer": "The Stand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbd7", "question": "What South American country was a former member of OPEC?", "answer": "Ecuador", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c50e", "question": "What color is a giraffe's tongue?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133950f", "question": "Who voiced the character Atta in the movie \"A Bug's Life\"?", "answer": "Julia Louis Dreyfuss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339943", "question": "What is the first rule in the movie \"Fight Club\"?", "answer": "You don't talk about Fight Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133964c", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1943 movie \"My Friend Fllicka\"?", "answer": "Horse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339697", "question": "What TV family lived at Southfork Ranch?", "answer": "The Ewings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9fd", "question": "What did Gene Siskel and Roger Ebert do for a living?", "answer": "They were movie critics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac01", "question": "The Plains of Abraham is in which Canadian province?", "answer": "Quebec", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4ddd206d333868d34d709", "question": "Besides \"Axis Sally\", who was another famous propaganda broadcaster for the Nazis?", "answer": "Berlin Betty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a276", "question": "What US city is mentioned in the first line of the Bob Seger song \"Turn the Page\"?", "answer": "Omaha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133919d", "question": "Who was the voice of Donkey in the \"Shrek\" movie series?", "answer": "Eddie Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b17c", "question": "How old was politician Pierre Trudeau when he died in the year 2000?", "answer": "80", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3c2694f032c0db195b481", "question": "How old was Catherine of Aragon when she was betrothed to Prince Arthur?", "answer": "Catherine was three years old", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e72d1aad0874f1a5e2d1c2c", "question": "What band has the most No. 1 hits on \"The Billboard Hot 100\" with 20 songs to reach No. 1?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe767e7eec85e375820b29a", "question": "What is the world's widest river?", "answer": "Amazon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a552ad3e1c6f9840ba319a", "question": "Which country has the calling code 82?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa7", "question": "Which vegetable is the principal ingredient of rosti?\u00a0", "answer": "Potato\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d246bb53d1af65886507", "question": "Which star is represented by placing a star on top of a Christmas tree?", "answer": "Star of Bethlehem", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd7", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"rodeo\"?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea43c6ff048f679a45ab88", "question": "What is the breakdown of a material by separation of the layers of which it is composed called?", "answer": "Delamination", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c676", "question": "What is the largest member of the deer family living in the US?", "answer": "The moose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e6", "question": "Which company holds the ticker symbol \"FUN\" on the New York Stock Exchange?", "answer": "Cedar Point", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c885", "question": "How many arms does a squid have?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59220369a4edfd43a087ade2", "question": "Marzipan is made of which ground nut?", "answer": "Almond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ca", "question": "What bird, also known as a Man O'War, can glide for hours without flapping its wings?", "answer": "Magnificent Frigatebird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bda", "question": "Mark Wahlberg has a tattoo of what popular musician on his left shoulder?", "answer": "Bob Marley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6696ba5bfecdd737e087b", "question": "What was Scrabble originally called?", "answer": "Lexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7736ceec85e375820b307", "question": "Which U.S. state is closest to the Tropic of Cancer?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a565", "question": "Which US state is home to the Pebble Beach Golf Links?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d66e2596a59cbdfbd3aa", "question": "What organization unveiled the largest machine on Earth in 2008?", "answer": "CERN", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c842", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the medulla?", "answer": "The brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac07", "question": "In which continent would you find the Congo River?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c73b877e98cb977789c9", "question": "Which national capital does the Vltava River flow through?", "answer": "Prague", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e8a806d333868d34d74c", "question": "Where can you find Pont Du Gard, part of an ancient Roman aqueduct?", "answer": "N\u00eemes, France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5902a033cad1ec93f27df768", "question": "What is typically added to Vietnamese iced coffee to sweeten it?", "answer": "Sweetened condensed milk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc34cec223966ae8f887d", "question": "Tiger Woods set or tied 27 records at which 1997 PGA tournament?", "answer": "The Masters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c5", "question": "What 2009 movie takes place on a moon named \"Pandora\"?", "answer": "Avatar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c213", "question": "Which country were the 1928 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Netherlands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a682", "question": "Which states share a border with South Carolina?", "answer": "Georgia and North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c049", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Argentina?", "answer": "Rufous Hornero", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8d5412b42d4a3561a9f00", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is the name of Francine\u2019s daughter?", "answer": "Jenny", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d0", "question": "Who was sent to the electric chair on the testimony of her brother David Greenglass?", "answer": "Ethel Rosenberg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c39", "question": "What is the name of the cafe in the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Central Perk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff14015b0ee8c595b6d3994", "question": "In what city was the Diary of Anne Frank written?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4cb", "question": "How much does the adult giraffe heart weigh?", "answer": "25 lbs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0e562fcbed638185eaa2e", "question": "Where can you take part in the \"Battle of the Oranges\"?", "answer": "Ivrea, Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd4", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"P\"?", "answer": "Papa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdaf5ec223966ae8f88ee", "question": "Which film earned Stanley Kubrick a Razzie nomination for Worst Director?", "answer": "\"The Shining\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c172", "question": "What does a dowser do?", "answer": "Find water", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b19", "question": "What is the first book of the New Testament?", "answer": "The Gospel According to St. Matthew", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede0ee6ce05a3942286dbe", "question": "What is the name of the serial killer in the film \"The Silence of the Lambs\"?", "answer": "Buffalo Bill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c7", "question": "How old was Sean Connery when he first appeared as James Bond?", "answer": "32", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a19", "question": "What UK band had a #1 hit in 1981 with the song \"Don\u2019t You Want Me\"?", "answer": "Human League", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc14", "question": "What year was the social giant Facebook founded?", "answer": "2004", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c809", "question": "How many pairs of chromosomes are there in each human cell?", "answer": "23", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a36", "question": "On what show did Heather Locklear make her TV debut in a recurring role?", "answer": "Dynasty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd81bbdd0de9af39e9d467c", "question": "Who was the first president to have electricity in the White House?", "answer": "Benjamin Harrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d0", "question": "What is the only mammal with four knees?", "answer": "The Elephant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015eaccfe83fe1f2a824bf5", "question": "What does the color blue represent in the American flag?", "answer": "Blue symbolizes vigilance, perseverance and justice.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393aa", "question": "What movie was Sean Penn's directorial debut?", "answer": "Indian Runner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c807", "question": "What grapefruit-sized object has been reckoned to be the largest single cell on earth?", "answer": "An ostrich egg yolk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a901", "question": "The majority of the World's real cinnamon comes from what island nation?", "answer": "Sri Lanka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c8", "question": "The singer Shakira comes from what country?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a1b", "question": "Will Smith, Charlize Theron, and Jack Lemmon were all featured in what movie?", "answer": "The Legend of Bagger Vance", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76ffceec85e375820b2f2", "question": "In which city was the 2000 movie \"Gladiator\" filmed?", "answer": "Ouarzazate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339037", "question": "What is non-rhyming poetry called?", "answer": "Blank verse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ec", "question": "Which TV production company brought the show \"Late Night With David Letterman\" to NBC?", "answer": "Worldwide Pants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ee", "question": "Which celebrity launched a perfume range entitled \"M\" in 2007?", "answer": "Mariah Carey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca6f", "question": "To which tree family does the osier belong?", "answer": "Willow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e7", "question": "What is the longest one syllable word in the English language?", "answer": "Screeched", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1bf", "question": "Who was Charles Edward Anderson Berry better known as?", "answer": "Chuck Berry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5f8f6ce05a3942286e44", "question": "What was the original name of the Boston Red Sox?", "answer": "Boston Americans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c800", "question": "By what common name is sodium bicarbonate otherwise known?", "answer": "Baking Soda", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59636de7967692ea851899b0", "question": "What is the name of Rascal Flatts\u2019 10th studio album?", "answer": "\"Back To Us\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1ac7baab681b09292196", "question": "Which car is considered to be the first hot hatchback, introduced in the 1970s?", "answer": "The Simca 1100 TI", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a2", "question": "On which US coast can Redwood trees be found?", "answer": "West coast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015dfe5fe83fe1f2a824b83", "question": "What year was the fire extinguisher invented?", "answer": "1723", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339119", "question": "Who is the protagonist of H. G. Wells' \"The Island of Doctor Moreau\"?", "answer": "Edward Prendick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1bd", "question": "How old was John Lennon when he was murdered?", "answer": "40", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c0d2877e98cb97778970", "question": "What is the longest river in the UK?", "answer": "Severn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e9", "question": "In which country would you find the world's oldest golf course?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bfdffe3b668d7dfe168b5bd", "question": "Chablis wine comes from which French wine region?", "answer": "Burgundy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b60", "question": "What is the highest female voice in a choir?", "answer": "Soprano", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4b4549076251badbeac1", "question": "Who was the first female U.S. Attorney General?", "answer": "Janet Reno -- She served as the attorney general for President Bill Clinton's entire presidency.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f1", "question": "What happens when you roll three consecutive doubles in a game of Monopoly?", "answer": "You go to jail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339218", "question": "What is the theme song of the TV show \"Friends\" called?", "answer": "I'll Be There for You by The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b933", "question": "What meal-in-a-box is called the San Francisco treat?", "answer": "Rice-a-Roni", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c98", "question": "Who was the Greek god of the sea?", "answer": "Poseidon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdc0d1c469bb8041d07a058", "question": "Which country did ices or sorbets originate in?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590681e5ff9c0647b50a8098", "question": "What fictional town is the Netflix series \"Stranger Things\" based in?", "answer": "Hawkins, Indiana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca3b", "question": "Which element appears seventh on the periodic table?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81c", "question": "In what part of the body would you find aqueous humour?", "answer": "The eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d5", "question": "What musical is set at Rydell High?", "answer": "Grease", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b293", "question": "What European country ruled Macau until December 20, 1999?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa55a3c73aa70ea0b70b24", "question": "Sahti is a type of beer that is traditionally flavored with juniper and it is most likely found in which country?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}]